University of Arizona land-grant centennial records 1960-1962
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
University of Arizona Land-Grant centennial records 1960-1962
AZ 032
University of Arizona
Correspondence, administrative papers, photographs, newspaper clippings, publications, records of events, informational and promotional materials for the University of Arizona’s participation in the centennial convocation of the American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities
4.2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Historical Note
University of Arizona recognition of 100 years of land-grant colleges and universities, 1862-1962, and the university’s participation in the centennial convocation of the American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities held at Kansas City, 1961.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 7 series
Series I: General Files, 1960-1961.
Series II: Publicity materials, 1960-1961.
Series III: College histories.
Series IV: Story of research.
Series V: National.
Series VI: Kansas City Convocation (other institutions).
Series VII: Miscellaneous, 1960-1962.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, administrative papers, photographs, newspaper clippings, publications, records of events, informational and promotional material, programs and publications from other institutions, records of the centennial convocation of American Association of Land Grant Colleges and State Universities in Kansas City, Nov. 12-16, 1961; and manuscripts of two projected publications about the University of Arizona: The Story of Research, and College Histories.
Access Terms
University of Arizona -- Records and correspondence.
University of Arizona -- History.
University of Arizona -- Anniversaries, etc.
University of Arizona -- Research.
University of Arizona. College of Agriculture.
University of Arizona. School of Home Economics.
University of Arizona. College of Education.
University of Arizona. College of Engineering.
University of Arizona. College of Fine Arts.
University of Arizona. College of Law.
University of Arizona. College of Liberal Arts.
University of Arizona. College of Pharmacy.
University of Arizona. College of Nursing.
University of Arizona. Graduate College.
University of Arizona. Dept. of Military Science and Tactics.
University of Arizona. Library.
University of Arizona. Dept. of Physical Education for Women.
University of Arizona. Dept. of Health, Physical Education and Recreation.
University of Arizona. Faculty.
University of Arizona. Agricultural Experiment Station.
American Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities.
State universities and colleges – Arizona.
Arizona -- History.
Container List
- Series I: General Files,1960-1962
  - Announcement. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Committee. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scheduled Events (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Committees. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Lecturers (Visiting). (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Survey: U of A Graduate Report. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Survey: Foreign Student Opinion. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Projects: Miscellaneous. Proposed. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Projects: Rejected. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Science Library Mural. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fact Book. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Natural History Survey (Arizona). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Map: Land Grant. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Materials Folder. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Home Economics Folder. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - “The Spirit of the Land Grant Institutions” Reprint. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Concurrent Celebrations. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series II: Publicity 1960-1962
  - Governmental Acts and Proclamations (Historic and current). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Clippings; Publicity; Events. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Television – Radio. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wildcat, September 17, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series III: Publicity 1960-1962
  - College Histories, publication of: (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - College of Agriculture (General, School of Home Economics, Agricultural Extension Service). (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - College of Agricultural (Agricultural Extension Stations). (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - College of Business and Public Administration. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - College of Education. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - College of Engineering. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - College of Fine Arts. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - College of Law. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - College of Liberal Arts. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - College of Pharmacy. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Graduate College. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - School of Nursing. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bureaus, Laboratories, Institutes, etc. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Library and University of Arizona Faculty. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - School of Military Sciences and Tactics. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Physical Education (men). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Physical Education (men). (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory of Tree Ring Research (Tribute to Dr. Andrew.E. Douglass). (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Story of research, 1961-1962
  - Research story, publication of: (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - College of Agriculture. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - College of BPA. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - College of Education. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - College of Engineering. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - College of Fine Arts. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - College of Liberal Arts. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - College of Mines. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - College of Pharmacy. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Special Divisions. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series V: National.
  - Miscellaneous Releases by National Land-Grant Office. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Addresses (Manuscripts). (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - “High Education” Reprint. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Publications. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Citizens Seminars. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Contributions to National Centennial Fund. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Mass Mailer (Washington Issue). (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Table Top Display (from Washington). (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - “Next Year is Now” – Centennial Film. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Series VI:Kansas City Convocation (other institutions).
  - Kansas City Convocation. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Kansas City Convocation: Speeches. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Kansas City Convocation: Art and Book Exhibits. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series VII:Kansas City Convocation (other institutions). 1961-1962
  - Other institutions: Programs. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Other institutions: Sample materials and publications. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - . (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Pictorial Record. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Paperweight Souvenir. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Seals and Proofs. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Motion Picture “New Horizon”. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Framed Painting of Justin S. Morrill. (Box 7)
  - Table top display. (Box 8)